<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tutorial on Joyce Kung</title><link>https://joyce.fyi/categories/tutorial/</link><description>Recent content in tutorial on Joyce Kung</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 21:36:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joyce.fyi/categories/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a chmod calculator in Go</title><link>https://joyce.fyi/posts/modch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 21:36:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://joyce.fyi/posts/modch/</guid><description>One of the things that really irked me as I started to learn more about Linux was using the chmod command.
When I first learned the chmod command in school, we learned to explicity declare the permissions:
$ chmod a+x file.txt However, whenever running through tutorials or, really, anything that involved chmod, I found that most people like to use the numeric (octal) format instead1:
$ chmod 777 file.txt I knew there was some kind of math involved with chmod, so I decided it would be fun to try writing a chmod calculator in Go, a language I started learning this summer.</description></item><item><title>Linux Upskill Challenge: Setting up on Google Cloud Platform</title><link>https://joyce.fyi/posts/linux-upskill-setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 14:02:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://joyce.fyi/posts/linux-upskill-setup/</guid><description>This September1, I&amp;rsquo;m going to participate in the Linux Upskill Challenge. I read about it a little on Hacker News yesterday, and it looks like it aligns really well with my goals of working as an SRE.
The challenge starts tomorrow, so today is &amp;ldquo;Day 0&amp;rdquo; of 20: getting set up. It&amp;rsquo;s possible that I may create new posts related to this challenge - even though the content is listed publicly on Github at all times - but we&amp;rsquo;ll see at the end of this month.</description></item></channel></rss>